（あおい）
靴下どこ～？
Where's my sock?
Why is it always one sock that disappears every time?
なんで靴下は
片っぽだけ行方不明になるのか
If they vanished in pairs,
I'd be able to let it go more easily.
も～う両方なくなれば
諦めもつくのに
This will do.
これでいいや
…っと
Oh, my phone.
あっ ケータイ ケータイ
Sis
Incoming Call
Hello?
Oh, look at that! You're actually awake!
（かおり）
あ～ ビックリした
あんた起きてたの？
Of course I am. I've got work.
そりゃ起きてるよ 仕事だもん
Really? I thought anime studios started work in the evening.
（かおり）
え～ 夕方
やっと始まるんじゃないの？
アニメの会社って
Not us.
うちは違うの
みんな ちゃんと10時出社だし
We all have to be there by 10. The president is a stickler about morning meeting attendance.
社長も朝礼
絶対 全員出席って言うし
Wow, sounds like a real company!
（かおり）
へえ～ ビックリ　会社っぽいね
We are a real company!
Is this all you wanted to talk about?!
会社だよ！
ねいちゃん それが言いたくて
電話かけてきたの？
No! I called because I'm heading over today!
（かおり）
違うよ あのさ―
私 今日そっちへ行くから
（あおい）え！
You mean here?
そっちって！　え？　今日？
Wait, today?
（新幹線の発車ベル）
（かおり）あっ 新幹線 来た
Oh, the bullet train just arrived!
But I won't be home!
私 家いないよ
It's okay. Just put a spare key in the mailbox or something!
（かおり）
大丈夫
ポストかどっかに入れといて～
What do you mean, "or something"?!
どっかって～！
Thanks in advance!
（かおり）
頼むね～
I am not just leaving it in the mailbox!
（あおい）
ポストって
そんなわけいかないよ～
Good morning, Oi-chan-senpai!
おはようございます
おいちゃん先輩
よかった りーちゃん起きてて
I'm so glad you're awake!
I was just about to go to sleep, actually.
いや これから寝るとこっす
ドストの「罪と罰」
マジ面白くって徹夜なんです
Dost's Crime and Punishment was just so good,
I ended up pulling an all-nighter.
Dost... oyevsky?
ドスト… エフスキー？
Raskolnikov's character is so well written!
ラスコーリニコフ
マジ キャラ立ってます
So what's the problem?
なんかトラブルでも？
あっ 今日 家にいる？
昼くらいまで
Are you gonna be home until around, say, noon?
Yeah! I'm making today Dost day!
ます！　今日はドスト祭りです
Can you give this to my sister?
じゃあ これ ねいちゃんに
渡してくれないかな
ねいちゃん？
かおちゃんねいさんですか？
Your sister?
Oh yeah, Kao-chan-neesan?
She called saying she's on her way.
いきなり今日 来るって言うの
Same as ever. Comes and goes like the breeze, huh?
さっすが
相変わらず突発的っすね
I know, right?
そうなんだよ
Okie dokie! Just leave it to me!
うぃ～っす 分かりました
Huh?
（あおい）
あれ？　絵麻(えま)もう来てるんだ 早い
Ema's here already?
So early...
Good morning.
（杉江(すぎえ)）
おはよう
Good morning!
（絵麻）
おはようございます
Cat Retake
Today, the copy machine will be undergoing maintenance.
（興津(おきつ)）
本日 コピー機の
メンテナンスが入ります
It will be unavailable from 13:00 to about 14:00,
so be sure to run what you need to before then.
13時から１時間ほどかかる
見込みですので
作業は早めに
済ませておいてください
Now, Ochiai-kun has a bit of an announcement.
それと落合(おちあい)君から話があります
For personal reasons, I, Ochiai Tatsuya,
will leave Musashino Animation at the end of this week.
わたくし落合達也(たつや)は
一身上の都合により
今週いっぱいで
武蔵野(むさしの)アニメーションを
離れることになりました
長い間 お世話になりました
Thank you for all you've done for me.
Thanks for working with us.
（丸川(まるかわ)）
お疲れさまでした
Good luck!
（渡辺(わたなべ)）頑張れよ
（あおい）えっ
Wait, what's going on?!
（太郎(たろう)）
え～！　なんすか
どうゆうことっすか
"Personal reasons" doesn't tell us anything!
一身上って
説明になってないっすよ～
（矢野(やの)）
うるさいよ　ムサニを
辞めるってことだよ
Shut up. He's quitting, and that's that.
辞めるって
ずっと一緒にやってきたのに
Quitting?! After all we've been through together?
Feels like my pet dog just bit my hand.
なんかもう 飼い犬に
手をかまれた気分っすよ
He's not a dog, much less yours!
（矢野）
犬かよ！　つか お前が飼い主かよ
I'd like to have a quick word with all the PAs after this meeting.
（本田(ほんだ)）
朝礼の後 進行は残ってください
It's about the upcoming schedule.
今後のスケジュールのことを
話すんで
This concludes today's morning meeting.
じゃあ ひとまず
朝礼を終わります
Okay, thanks.
（一同）
は～い
So that's how it is.
というわけで…
I can't accept this!
いや 俺
全然 納得してませんから
No one cares how you feel.
お前の納得はいいんだよ
As for redistributing work...
（本田）
引き継ぎなんだけど
Yano-san, you're in charge of handling episode 11 in place of Ochiai-kun.
矢野さんは落合君が持ってた―
「えくそだすっ！」11話を
担当してもらって
Got it.
（矢野）
はい
I'm giving you episode 12 then, Tarou.
私の12話は太郎
あんたがやるんだよ
Huh? Why?!
（太郎）
え？　なんで！
At times like these, work slides on down to the next person.
こういう場合
受け持ちがスライドするの
Everything's on schedule at this point,
so if you can't get filming done before dubbing,
ここまで順調なんだから
ダビングまでに
撮影 間に合わなかったら
you know what to expect.
分かってるよね？
えっ パワハラ？
Power harassment?
Oh, worse than that, for sure.
もっと ひどいことになるから
じゃあ セクハラ！
Sexual harassment?!
（本田）それで 宮森(みやもり)さん
（あおい）はい
And you, Miyamori-san.
Yes?
You get episode 13.
宮森さんは13話をお願いします
大変だけど よろしくね
It'll be tough, but you can do it.
But episode 13 is the finale, right?
でも13話って最終話ですよね
Is it really okay to have me working on such an important episode?
そんな大事な話数
私が担当していいんですか？
Isn't that great?
うわ～ いいな～　名誉の最終話
I wanted to do the final episode! All that sweet, yummy prestige!
俺やりたかったな～
イヒ～ フフフ
Sorry, Miyamori.
すまん 宮森
I wanted to see this through to the end, but...
放送 終わるまで
見届けたかったんだけど
It's fine.
あっ いえ…
And think of it this way: doing the final episode is something of an equivalent exchange.
（落合）
それと最終話の担当って
いわゆる等価交換だから
Survive hell and you get a smidgen of glory.
小さな名誉と大きな地獄の
えっ！　そうなんですか！
Seriously?!
ラッキー
セーフ セーフ セーフ… うっ
Sweet! Now I'm glad I didn't get it!
But you'll get an incredible amount of
experience too. I highly recommend it.
でも１回やれば自信になるから
進行経験としては おすすめ
何が おすすめなんだか
鬼畜だね 落合は
Are you going to "recommend" crucifixion next?
I guess you want to kill her.
分かってるよ マジすまん
I know, I know.
I'm really sorry.
なんすか！
そのお互い分かってる感は
Since when do you two get along so well?!
ハッ まさか結婚退職っすか？
Are you telling me...
you're quitting to go get hitched?
バカなの？　お前
Are you insane?
Well, that's it. Dismissed!
（本田）
はい 解散 解散
H-Hey, wait!
（太郎）
ちょっと～！
（山田(やまだ)）
いいね 瀬川(せがわ)さん
Segawa-san's doing a great job.
She could even start doing character designs.
そろそろキャラデとかやんないかな
Character designs?
キャラクターデザインですか？
Some keyframers want to eventually move on to design work,
原画マンにも
将来デザインやりたい人と
while others are happy to keep on animating.
ずっと動きを
追及したい人がいるから
余計なことかもしんないけど
So this might be a misplaced hope, but I'd love to see some original characters from her.
俺は一回 瀬川さんの
オリジナルキャラとか見てみたいな
Maybe you could use them when you direct!
じゃあ山田さんが監督やる時に
Me? I'm not really suited to be a director.
俺？　俺は監督に向いてないよ
My style is bland, and I don't have the confidence to spearhead a project.
作風地味だし
第一 矢面に立つ自信ないからね
Really? But the action scenes in episode 4 were amazing!
そんな！　４話のアクション
すごいじゃないですか
No, I've seen enough good and bad examples to know how it is.
いやいやいや いい見本も
悪い見本も見てるから
More than enough.
つか 見すぎちゃってるからな
（木下(きのした)）
ううっ！　落ちる
あと１時間 待って～
One more hour... Just one more hour...
アハハ…
Ochiai-san...
（あおい）落合さんも
（山田）うん？
Hm?
Did he see too many examples too?
落合さんも いろいろ
見すぎちゃったんでしょうか？
Oh, he's just transferring over to Canaan.
ああ あいつね
カナンに移るんだよ
Huh? Canaan?
（あおい）
え！　カナンて
あのカナンスタジオですか？
You mean the Canaan? They're such a major studio!
大手じゃないですか！
Does everyone already know?
みんな知ってるんですか？
Pretty much.
ああ もう大体ね
He was recruited? That's really impressive.
ヘッドハンティングですか～
すごいな～
Well, there's that original robot anime they're going to run next year.
いやいや 来年１月から始まる―
カナンのオリジナル
ロボットアニメがあるだろ？
Uh...
（あおい）
えっと…
RoboPub: The Robot I Built is Having a Hard Time Because of Puberty.
「ロボはる」
「俺の手作りロボットが
思春期で大変です」な
Right, that one!
あっ それです
It's a two-cour original anime,
（山田）
オリジナルで２(ツー)クールなのに
but storyboards were only done three days before editing—for episode 2!
コンテ上がるのは編集３日前
それも２話目から
Wow... Is that why Ochiai-san is going to Canaan?
（あおい）
うわ～ 落合さんは
それでカナンに？
I think he was planning on going once Exodus was finished.
もともと「えくそだすっ！」
終わらせてから
移るつもりでいたんじゃない？
But judging by the timing...
でも この時期ってことは多分…
Sounds like it's gonna be really rough.
大変じゃないですか
I guess so.
まあな
The line producer at Canaan is
Ochiai's senior from university.
カナンのラインＰと落合って
もともと大学の先輩後輩で
長いつきあいだし
Probably couldn't say no when his old acquaintance begged.
泣きつかれたら断れないだろ
But that schedule sounds way worse than Exodus's.
でも そのスケジュールって
「えくそだすっ！」より
悪いじゃないですか
You bet, but it's still not as bad as BoingPara's was.
悪い 悪い
でも「ぷる天」よりはマシ
I've only heard the stories about Boing-Boing Paradise.
話には聞きますけど
伝説の「ぷるんぷるん天国」
Was it really that bad?
そんなに大変だったんですか？
A legend is born
The animator went mad while drawing keyframes
The schedule collapsed and the animation just melted.
（山田）
崩壊するスケジュール
とろける動画　３度の総集編
Boing-Nine
Abbreviation of Boing-Boing Paradise Episode 9
It's an epic episode in multiple (mostly negative) ways.
Some say that there won't be another piece of animation with such QUALITY. Creepy BG-only scenes, surreal wobbling of boobs and numerous other incomprehensible
We were forced to have three recap episodes.
The official blog got flamed.
There was a BPO and a PTA case too.
公式ブログ炎上
ＢＰＯにＰＴＡ事件
Horror Alert
The animator broke down at this point
そして納品拒否
In the end, the show was rejected by broadcasters.
Dear world, this is animation!
During the whole ordeal, I almost never left the studio for three whole months.
俺は結果的に３か月連続
スタジオ泊まり込み
My landlord thought I had completely lost it and called my parents.
30過ぎて不審に思った大家から
親に連絡いったとか
The mold in my rice cooker started turning a strange color.
炊飯器にカラフルなカビが
発生してたとかな～
That was the one and only time I've seen that level of hell...
（山田）
あんな地獄は
後にも先にもないね～
（山田）まだ…
（あおい）まだって山田さん！
so far.
Quit trying to scare me, Yamada-san!
不吉なこと
言わないでください！
Okay, let's drop the subject.
やめよう この話
Talking about other schedules jinxes your own.
よそのスケジュール
ディスってたら
絶対ブーメラン
返ってくるもんなんだよ
これ業界あるあるな
That's what they say, you know.
イヤです！　明日は我が身！
No way! It's only my first time!
Right. Just remember to do
everything the best you can.
（山田）
そうそう　自分のことだけ
一生懸命にやるのが一番
How many keyframe cuts are gonna be done today?
今日 原画はどれだけ
上がってくる予定？
Twenty-four.
（あおい）
24です
う～ん ちょっと厳しいな
ケツに固めないでくれよ
That's a lot.
Don't leave it all until the deadline.
I know.
（あおい）
分かりました
By the way, you need to get the director to pick up the pace with episode 13.
あとな 13話
本気で監督のケツ
たたいたほうがいいぞ
The storyboards for part B still aren't done.
絵コンテＢパート
まだ上がってないだろ
ハッ 絵コンテがどこにもない！
I don't see any storyboards!
He feels bad about the delays, so he's hiding his work.
進みが悪いから隠してんだよ
He's resorted to that?
そんな ちびくさいマネを？
Basically, yeah.
Kinoshita Seiichi will do anything when cornered.
追い込まれた木下誠一(せいいち)は
なんだってするさ
（あおい）
うっ… 監督 絵コンテは？
Director, where are the storyboards?
うぐぐ… 大丈夫 大丈夫
It's okay!
I'll make it on time!
間に合う 間に合う
来月には絶対…
In the next month...
Next month? That's past when the episode airs!
来月って放送 終わっちゃいますよ
Then the month after...
（木下）
じゃっ 再来月…
What should I do?
（宮森）
どうすればいいんでしょう
Fight the good fight, Miyamori!
（山田）ファイトだ 宮森
（あおい）え～！
Roasted tea?
ほうじ茶
Cats are hard to draw.
（杉江）
ネコは難しいよね
Ever had one as a pet before?
ネコ 飼ったことない？
I haven't.
ないです
I see.
そうか
You know, there's a certain way cats walk.
ネコはね
足の運びに法則があって…
Ema!
（あおい）
絵麻
Oi-chan?
（絵麻）
あっ おいちゃん
How are the keyframes coming?
残りの原画なんだけど
I'm working on them now.
うん 今やってる
How is it going? Are they still gonna be done on time?
（あおい）
調子は どんな感じ？
いつくらいに上がりそうかな？
えっと 急げばなんとか…
Well... If I hurry, I should be okay.
Really?
（あおい）ホント？
（絵麻）でも―
But I want to hand in this scene's cuts all together.
このシーンまとめて出したいし
I know I said you had a week to get them done,
今週いっぱいって言ってたけど
but at this rate Segawa-san and Yamada-san are gonna have a hard time.
このままいくと瀬川さんと
山田さんのチェックが
大変になりそうで
To help them out, it'd be great to get each one in as soon as it's done.
なるべく２人の負担を
減らしたいから
ちょっとずつでも
もらえるとうれしい
Segawa-san?
（絵麻）瀬川さんの？
（あおい）うん
Yeah!
She'll get it done on time, I'm sure.
最終的には瀬川さんが
間に合わせてくれると思うんだけど
She's amazing! Fast and top notch!
すごいよね 早くて うまくて
It's Kisa-san.
木佐(きさ)さんだ　じゃあ お願い 絵麻
I'm counting on you, Ema!
Miyamori speaking.
はい 宮森です
Huh? You strained your leg?
え？　肉離れ？
Your leg and not your hand, right?
It's Thursday, so... ten cuts this week?
（絵麻）
今日が木曜で
今週いっぱいで10カット
You can only develop the speed in your hands while you're young.
（杉江）
若い時でないと手の早さは
身につけられないからね
Now's the time to give it your all.
今が頑張り時だよ
Huh? But don't I get faster with experience?
うまくなれば早く描けるように
なるんじゃないんですか？
You need to become a better artist before getting faster.
早く描くには うまくなる
To become a better artist, you need to draw more.
うまく描くには いっぱい描く
But to draw more, you need to start drawing faster.
いっぱい描くには 早く描く
Technical skill and speed are two very different things.
技術とスピードは
実は まったく別の問題でね
Even if you develop your skill over the years, your speed won't change that much.
年取って技術を身につけても
一日に描ける量は
そうは変わらない
You might even get slower.
むしろスピードは落ちていく
周りにうってつけの
手本がいるじゃないか
You've got plenty of great examples to follow though.
Ogasawara-san and Iguchi-san both overcame the same obstacle you're facing.
小笠原(おがさわら)さんや井口(いぐち)さん
彼女らも安原(やすはら)さんと同じ
壁を乗り越えてきたんだから
You should ask them for advice.
相談に乗ってもらえばいい
But...
そんな…
You can focus on the details of your work once you've improved your pace.
（杉江）
仕事へのこだわりは
手の早さを手に入れてから
少しずつだな
So I can get away with mediocre work?
最初は下手でも
しかたないんですか？
If that work can meet the episode director's requirements.
それは演出からオーケーがもらえる
基準はクリアしないと
If you can do that, you make a living.
それができれば食べられる
If you can't, you quit.
できなければ辞めていく
That's what it means to be an animator.
アニメーターは そういう仕事だよ
Sounds harsh...
怖い…
I'm just an old man who missed his chance to quit, though.
まあ僕なんか辞め時を見失った
ロートルだけどね
Huh, so this is Tokyo?
（かおり）
うわ～ ここ東京？
うちと そう変わらないじゃん
It's not much different from where I live.
あっ 絵麻ちゃ～ん
Ema-chan!
Welcome, Miyamori Kaori-sama!
"Welcome, Miyamori Kaori-sama!"
（かおり）
“歓迎！　宮森かおり様”
Welcome, Miyamori Kaori-sama!
"Please come to room 301."
“301号室にお越しください”？
Long time no see, Rii-chan!
あっ お久し りーちゃん
ウフフ
Hello, Kao-chan-neesan.
どうも かおちゃんねいさん
鍵 預かってます　ふわ～
I've got the key for you.
I wonder if that actually was Ema-chan.
（かおり）
あれ 絵麻ちゃんじゃ
なかったのかな？
It probably was.
（みどり）
いや 多分 本物
Really?
（かおり）
そうなの？
（みどり）
お昼 家で食べたり
She usually goes home for lunch.
No way! That's pretty cool!
へえ～ まめ！　偉い
She's just trying to save money.
（みどり）
節約してるらしいです
（かおり）
へえ～ 案外キレイにしてんじゃん
This place is way cleaner than I thought it would be.
So do you have the day off?
かおりゃんねいさん
お休みなんですか？
ま～さか　信金職員が
平日 休みのわけないじゃん
No way!
Fresh meat like me could never take a break at the company!
有給 有給 ヘヘッ
I took paid leave.
Here, Don-Don-Donuts.
はい どんどんドーナツ
（みどり）
おいちゃん先輩 喜びます
Oi-chan-senpai will love this.
It's like she left her tongue in the country.
あの子ね～
なんか味覚が田舎なんだよね
I bet she could get fancier and tastier stuff around here if she wanted.
もっとオシャレで おいしいもの
いっぱいあると思うんだけど
さてと ゆるむか
Time to relax.
The bathroom's over here, right?
お風呂こっち？
（みどり）はい
（かおり）おっ
Yeah.
Oh?
まだ こいつらいたの？
She still has these?
Sure brings back memories.
懐かし～
You're amazing, Ema!
（あおい）
すごいよ 絵麻
さっすが！　ありがとう
Really! Thanks a lot!
It's not everything though. Just four cuts.
全部じゃなくて４カットだけど
By the way, are you done for today?
（あおい）そうだ　今日は上がる？
（絵麻）うん？
My sister's visiting. Wanna come hang out?
（あおい）
ねいちゃんが来てるんだ
ちょっと寄ってかないかなと思って
（絵麻）
もうちょっと やってくつもり
I wanted to work a little more.
That's fine. Maybe next time.
そっか　じゃあ また改めて
（あおい）
ただいま～
I'm home!
（かおり）
おっきゃえり～
Welcome home!
What a hard-working gal!
お仕事ご苦労さん
（あおい）ふう～
（みどり）お疲れっす～
Hi!
The sea urchin can!
（あおい）
あっ うに缶！　うに缶 開いてる！
You opened it?!
It's too much for one sitting.
一気に食べるには多いよね これ
I was saving it for a special occasion!
スペシャルな時に
食べようと思ってたのに！
今日がスペシャルじゃん
私が来たんだから
What, me coming over isn't special enough?
ねいちゃん それ私の服！
Hey, those are my clothes!
I'm just borrowing them!
借りたよ～
And...
それに！
ねいちゃん シャンプー使った？
You used the shampoo too.
（かおり）
おん オグルビーって書いてあった
Yeah, it had "Ogilvy" written on it.
スペシャルな時に
使おうと思ってたのに！
I was saving that for a special occasion too!
何 この子やらしい
スペシャルな時だって
Ooh, naughty! You sound desperate for this "special occasion"!
（あおい）違う！
（かおり）う～ん
That's not what...
Seeing you two like that sure takes me back.
（みどり）
うわ～ 懐かしい この感じ
Listening to the two of you go on is so soothing.
おいちゃん先輩と
かおちゃんねいさんの会話
聞いてると癒やされます
Oh, come on.
（かおり）
どこが
I was in such a good mood before I got here, too.
せっかく気分よく帰ってきたのに
ううっ おいしいよ～
This is so good!
気分よくって
なんか いいことあったんですか？
Oh, did something nice happen?
Well, everything went according to schedule at work today.
うんとね 今日は仕事が
予定どおり順調に進んで
Huh? But things are supposed to go according to schedule.
はあ？
予定どおりって当たり前でしょ
They are!
（あおい）
分かってる！
分かってるけど ねいちゃん
They are, but you know...
あのね 予定どおりってことは
ものすっごく
It's very, very rare that things actually do stay on track.
ものすごく珍しいことなんだよ！
You poor thing! Eat up!
ふびんな子… まあ食え
Don't give me your pity!
かわいそがらないでよ
うに缶 うちのだし
And that's my sea urchin.
Did Ema lose weight?
（かおり）
ちょっと痩せた？　絵麻ちゃん
Don't you think you're working her too hard?
そもそもさ～ あんた
絵麻ちゃん働かせすぎじゃないの？
Huh? That's not really my fault.
（あおい）
え～ そんなこと言われても
I'm not the one who decides who does what.
仕事の割りふりは私じゃないし
Ema-senpai really takes things seriously.
絵麻先輩 真面目っすから
I guess. I'd say she's in the longest.
まあね　今 一番
座席率が高いと思う
座席率？
In? What do you mean?
In the studio. At work.
座席にいる率
Wow, that's hardcore!
うひょ～ 働き者
That seriously, huh?
真面目か～
What's wrong?
何？　ねいちゃん
There are pros and cons to being that diligent.
真面目って
いいことと悪いことがあるんだよね
What do you mean?
どういうこと？
You'll find out eventually.
あんたたちには まだ分からんさ
Wait a second, Tarou!
ちょっと太郎
You still haven't called Shiroki-san?
お前まだ白木(しろき)さんに
連絡 取ってないんだって？
Pick up the phone, now!
早く電話しな
今日やろうと思ってたんすよ
I was getting around to it today!
（矢野）
アニメは そば屋じゃない
Schedules don't stretch like noodles.
That reminds me, is episode 11 gonna be all right?
（太郎）
矢野さんこそ
11話 大丈夫なんすか？
思い出した　太郎
今晩12話の引き継ぎやるぞ
Oh yeah!
Work
Mailbox
Inbox
Flagged
All Drafts
All Sent
Trash
Tarou, you're picking up episode 12 tonight.
Work
Mailbox
Inbox
Flagged
Work
All Drafts
All Sent
Trash
Mailbox
Inbox
Flagged
Work
All Drafts
All Sent
Trash
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Shinkawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Shinkawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Coloring In
Niikawa-san
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Yamada-san
Platina Link
Coloring In
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
Komoro Studio
AAAAA
Coloring In
[#9] Retakes
Re:
Coloring In
Yamada-san
Yano-san
Niikawa-san
Platina Link
Segawa-san
Coloring In
About yesterday's Yasuhara-san's cuts
Muscle strain
Re; Re
Kisa-san
Yano-san
勘弁してくださいよ～
Give me a break!
Today's the rush check of episode 8!
I don't have time for that!
今日８話のオールラッシュで
それどころじゃないっす
Tomorrow's episode 7's editing.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
When Ochiai comes back from the editing of 11, we'll get started.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Be sure to tell her that.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
Be sure to tell her that.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
Be sure to tell her that.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
They can't be given to tweeners
The cuts need to be redone.
Rushed work like this is not
acceptable at this point.
unless I basically redraw all of it.
Be sure to tell her that.
All four cuts she did yesterday need retakes?
昨日 出した４カット
全部リテーク
I appreciate that she did them so quickly,
（瀬川）
急いで 上げてくれたのは
いいんだけど
but it's not just an issue about individual cuts. It's how it was drawn as a whole in general.
個々のカットが
どうこうっていうより
原画の描き方自体の問題だから
（あおい）
あの それって…
What do you mean?
These are so rushed that the lines aren't really laid out in a sensible way.
これ 描き急いでるせいで
全部の線が なんとなくで
とりあえずなの　つまり
It'd be hell to do tweening with these.
動画がものすごく
拾いにくい線だってこと
The tween positions would be too hard to find and it'd all melt.
中割りしづらいし
動画が溶けちゃう
（あおい）
溶けちゃう…
Melting...
I understand. I'll be sure to tell her myself.
了解しました
この件については私から
You know, Yasuhara-san
（瀬川）
安原さんね
always came across to me as pretty good and diligent,
真面目で一生懸命な人だと
思ってたんだけど
so it's a real letdown.
ちょっとガッカリした
All the precision and attention to detail
she had before are missing from these cuts.
今回もらったカット
安原さんが もともと持ってた
真面目さとか几帳面(きちょうめん)さとか
全然なくなってるし
She shouldn't get used to drawing like this.
こんな手の抜き方 覚えちゃダメ
Right. I'll make sure to tell her all that myself.
分かりました　安原には
私から伝えておきます
うう… 何？　忘れ物？
Huh? Forgot something?
Did I really say that?
うん？　そんなこと言ったっけ？
Like I said, when you're too serious,
sometimes things work out and sometimes they don't.
言ったとおり 真面目が
いいほうに働くこともあれば
悪いほうに
働くこともあるって話
Tea
Grape
fruit
water
Tea
Grape
fruit
water
Tea
Grape
fruit
water
Tea
Grape
fruit
water
Grape
fruit
water
Tea
真面目な人ほど
自分を追いつめるし
People like that tend to get led astray and lose sight of themselves.
Grape
fruit
water
Grape
fruit
water
Grape
fruit
water
Grape
fruit
water
Grape
fruit
water
Grape
fruit
water
Grape
fruit
water
Grape
fruit
water
Grape
fruit
water
自分を見失いやすいじゃない？
Tea
What should you do?
どうすればって…
If you tell them, "You lost sight of it," they'd still have no idea what "it" is.
見失ってる人に気付けったって
何をって話になるし
That's really about all you can say, though.
見失ってるよって言うくらいしか
できないんじゃないの？
てか誰の話よ？
Who are we talking about anyway?
She hung up.
切れた　も～う
Geez.
リテーク？
１カットだけじゃなくて？
Retakes? And not just one cut?
Yeah. Segawa-san said, "They can't be given to tweeners unless I basically redraw all of it."
うん 瀬川さんがね
全部に修正入れないと
動画に回せない… みたいな
All of it? That means I failed as a keyframer.
全部？
それ… 原画マンとして
失格ってことだよね
Failed? No, just—
そんな！　失格とか…
That's exactly what it means.
（絵麻）
でも そういうことだよね
大丈夫だって　絵麻はすごいよ
It'll be okay! I mean, you're amazing!
Honda-san said it's very rare to get to do keyframes
たった１年半で
原画マンに上がれるって
after just a year and a half of working for the company!
うちの会社じゃ あんまりないって
本田さんが言ってたよ
I heard that Fukuyama Atsumi-san started doing keyframes after two months.
（絵麻）
福山(ふくやま)アツミさんとか
２か月で
もう原画だったって聞くし
But Fukuyama-san... She's like a prodigy!
福山さんは あの人は
もう天才じゃない
（絵麻）
そうだよね　私は違うし
Right... and I'm not.
That's not what I meant!
絵麻が天才じゃないっていう
意味じゃなくて
What did Segawa-san say?
瀬川さん なんて言ってた？
That you shouldn't get used to drawing like this.
こういうやり方はよくないって
She was worried that something happened to you, since you're usually so careful and precise.
いつもは丁寧に
描いてくれてるのに
どうしたんだろうって
心配してくれてた
It's my fault for making you hurry. I'm sorry.
私がせかしたから… ごめん
だからリテークは絵麻が
いつもやってるみたいに
What I'm trying to say is that if you do the retakes as carefully as you usually work, it'll be fine!
丁寧にやってくれれば大丈夫
だから…
Okay?
But if I draw carefully, I just can't make it on time!
（絵麻）
でも私 丁寧に描いてたら
時間が いくらあっても足りない
I'll never get faster. I'll never have time to improve.
このままじゃ いつまでたっても
スピードが上がらない
I'll become a useless animator who excels at nothing. I can't make a living like that.
技術も磨けない
どっちつかずの
使えないアニメーターになって
食べていけない
I... I think you're being a bit too critical of your work.
多分！　多分だけど
絵麻が考えてるのは
すごくレベルが高いことで
Maybe you don't have to push yourself that far.
でも きっと
そこまで描く必要はなくて…
"That far"? Then how far should I?
（絵麻）
そこまでって どこまで？
えっと…
What if Segawa-san hates me?
（絵麻）
私 瀬川さんに嫌われてるのかな
なんで？
Where did that come from?
I had to do retakes for episode 4 too.
（絵麻）
だって４話も戻されたし
She'd never be judgmental like that for no good reason!
好きとか嫌いとかで
仕事する人じゃないよ
Really? But we all have things we like and dislike.
（絵麻）
そうかな
（絵麻）好き嫌いは普通じゃない？
（あおい）え？
And we have our own stylistic preferences.
好きな絵とか嫌いな絵とかって
絶対あるし
There's nothing surprising about
Segawa-san disliking my drawings.
瀬川さんにとって私の絵がそうでも
全然おかしくない
If an AD hates the work of a newbie keyframer like me, then it's all over.
私みたいな新人原画マンが
作監に嫌われたら―
おしまいだよね
（あおい）ハッ
It's not over! It's all right!
おしまいじゃないよ！
大丈夫だって！
But if I'm labeled as "useless", then I'll be out of work.
でも あの子は
使えないってなったら
仕事なんて どんどん減っちゃう
The big challenges are still ahead!
これからだよ これから
But I have to get through this
before I can face them.
でも 今の先に
これからがあるんだもん
If I'm bad now, then I'll always be bad!
今がダメだと
これからは よくならないよ
I'm a professional. It's not about trying my best.
プロなんだもん
一生懸命やればいい
ってわけじゃない
I think...
（あおい）
私は！　私は…
I think you're amazing just for having a goal for the future.
絵麻が ずっと先のこと
考えてるだけでも
すごいって思うよ
You know you want to become like Horiuchi-san. That's so clear-cut.
堀内(ほりうち)さんみたいになりたいとか
具体的な名前が出てくるじゃん
I can't even get my head around tomorrow, let alone think about the future!
私なんか今日と あしたのことで
もういっぱいいっぱいだもん
What are your plans for the future?
おいちゃんの
これからっていうのは？
（あおい）
え！　え…
これからって え～っと…
My plans? You mean once Exodus is over?
「えくそだすっ！」が
終わってから？
In general.
（絵麻）最終的に
（あおい）最終的？
In general?
なんだろう？
私の最終目標って
I don't know. What am I working towards?
I've got to get back to work.
仕事に戻らなきゃ　あとで食べるね
I'll eat this later.
（絵麻）あっ…
（井口）おっと
Watch out!
（井口）危ないよ～
（絵麻）うっ…
これ安原っちの？　返す？
Is this yours, Yasuharacchi?
Want it back?
う～ん じゃあ いただき
Guess it's mine now.
What's wrong?
どうした？
Tada!
ジャ～ン！
お～ なんか結婚式に
行く人みたいっす
You look like you're going to a wedding!
A wedding? I like that! Wanna go?
結婚式いいね　行っちゃう？
You got invited to one?
（みどり）
招待されてるんですか？
（かおり）ないけど
（みどり）え？
Nope.
Huh?
You try on something too!
りーちゃんも何か着てみなよ
I can't afford clothes like these.
こんないい服 買えないっす
（かおり）着るだけ着るだけ
（みどり）えっ
Just try them on!
Hey, hold on a second...
え？　あの かおちゃんねいさん
えっ ちょ…
Loading...
From
No Subject
Sis
Shopping with Rii-chan!
Hello, this is Musashino Animation.
I'm sorry, none of the production staff are in right now. I don't know.
Next time on Shirobako: "I Don't Mean to Reproach You."
I Don't Mean to Reproach You
（絵麻）
はい 武蔵野アニメーションです
すみません
今 制作の人いないので
分からないです
次回
「ＳＨＩＲＯＢＡＫＯ(シロバコ)」